WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
(BELL RINGS)
Oh. Hello, Edith, dear.
Hello, Granny. Isn't it exciting?
At my age one must ration one's excitement.
Oh.
I told her everything would come
right but she wouldn't believe me.
I still can't.
Something happening in this
house is actually about me.
The dress came this morning.
I was sad you decided against Patou.
I would've paid.
Lucile was safer. We don't want
her to look like a chorus girl.
How's Anthony? Excited,
I hope. Desperately.
Just when he thought his
life would never change,
he's going back to the beginning.
What an invigorating prospect!
I hope you've got your
shirt ready for tonight.
I've hidden a couple so I won't
be  caught out that way again.
Why should I be interested?
That goes for you, too. Me?
Take no notice.
Anna, are the flowers done?
Yes, I'll check them on Saturday
and lose any that's going over.
I've kept back a few in bud. I'll
be home for the dressing gong.
We'll manage.
Still no word from the doctor?
I'd have told you if there was.
They don't mind stringing it
out. Shall we got and see him?
Why? I'm sure if he knew
anything he would've said.
How are you today, Mr Molesley?
Oh.
Very well, thank you.
You were talking the other night
about your friend's daughter.
Is she still looking for a place? She is.
You read about the servant
shortage in the newspapers
but you can't find a situation
for a lady's maid. Not one.
She'll end up as a house
maid if she's not careful.
We can't have that. If I
were  to tell you something,
promise not to breathe  a word downstairs.
Miss O'Brien doesn't want  anyone to know.
How will they advertise it?
I don't know exactly.
Desirable nobleman's mansion
with surrounding estate and properties.
The house is pretty, we
might make something of it.
We could rename it Downton
Place. Who lives there now?
A tenant but we can come to an arrangement.
Let's take a picnic there tomorrow
on Edith's last day of freedom.
Molesley's in the hall.
Would you have a word?
I'll come through in a minute.
Not with you, with Mama.
Molesley.
Your Ladyship, may I have a word?
Of course.
My Lady, might I be allowed
to put forward a candidate
as Miss O'Brien's replacement? What?
When the time comes. Is O'Brien leaving?
I hope I've not spoken out of turn,
only I didn't want to miss
the chance. I thought you knew.
Of course I know, thank
you. I'll be happy to listen
to recommendations when the time comes.
Thank you, My Lady.
Well, I must confess, I'll watch
her departure with mixed emotions.
Mine are fairly unmixed. Did
you have a clue? Not a clue.
How very disappointing.
In a way it raises the big
question when do we tell the staff
that the end is nigh? It sounds so final.
I'm afraid it is final.
Well, don't spoil Edith's stay.
Let's get through the wedding
first then tell them afterwards.
Oh, Dr Clarkson.
Do you have a minute? Er, one minute, yes.
Do you mind if we... Only I know Mrs Hughes
is suffering from a condition
and I wondered if there's
anything I can do to help?
You can help by lessening her duties.
But you can't tell me how
serious it is? I'm afraid not.
Even if I knew, which I don't...
yet.
Good day to you, Mr Carson.
I had a telephone call
from Charkham earlier.
Charkham? Reggie Swire's lawyer.
The death certificate
has arrived from India.
He wants to bring it here. Can't
he send it? He wants to bring it.
He was quite definite.
I told him to come tomorrow.
There's nothing going on, is there?
You know there is, we're taking a picnic
to see the house we have to move into.
I'm surprised you, of all
people, can forget that. (SIGHS)
He's coming in the morning,
I won't put him off. Oh.
This is the moment when you receive
a huge fortune that could save Downton
and you give it away?
Will you choose where to
give it? I'd give it to Papa!
I hope in some small part of you you
can understand. I'm trying, really.
But I can't pretend I'm doing very well.
(DOOR OPENS AND CLOSES)
Will there be anything more, My Lady?
No.
Unless you have something
you want to tell me.
What might that be, My Lady?
I won't prompt you, O'Brien,
if you're not ready to say.
Did she tell you why? No.
Maybe she won't till she settles
where she's going but she has let me down.
We should go. Strallan won't be
late. He never is, worse luck. Oh.
I know you're not happy,
but Edith will be in the same county.
Loxley's a nice house, the
estate will give her plenty to do.
She'll be a nurse and by the time she's 50
she'll be wheeling
round a one-arm OLD man.
Are you waiting till they come
in search of the pudding? No.
Can I do something for you?
I'd better get back upstairs,
but, um, while you're here,
I saw Dr Clarkson today.
Oh?
I'm worried about Mrs Hughes.
We're all worried,
but I don't think he should've told you.
He said it would help if
we lessened her workload.
I'm sure it would but she won't
be pleased he's talked about her
before it's been confirmed.
So it is cancer? Not until it's confirmed.
Don't say anything. She'd hate
to think the doctor told you.
He didn't tell me, Mrs Patmore,
you told me.
(SIGHS)
Dear Edith... Edith tells me
you're very interested in politics.
Tom is our tame revolutionary.
Every family should have one.
As long as you are tame.
Tame enough for a game of billiards.
What about it?
Can you tell them where we've gone?
We're getting used to Tom
and I hope you will, too.
We haven't spoken, really,
since it was all settled.
I want you to know I quite
understand why you were against it.
Yes. Well...
I hope you believe I'll do my
best to make her happy. I do.
It was never personal. No, of course not.
No, it's just because of
all this and I'm far too old.
The thing is done, there's
no point raking it over.
But are you happy about it?
I'm happy Edith is happy, I'm
happy you mean to keep her happy.
That's enough happiness
to be going on with.
There's been a last-minute change
of mind about the wedding menus.
Couldn't Mrs Patmore do it?
She's given me her new order list.
She's done her job, it's
time for me to do mine.
I don't want you to get tired.
Who have you been speaking to?
No-one. What do you mean?
Nothing. I don't mean a
thing. Now, let me get on.
This is a simple stitch but
strong and very useful in a drama.
When do we get summat to eat?
As I was saying, you should start it
about half an inch away
from the centre line.
Oh, I'm glad you've come back.
I do hope you've come for our help.
You'd be so welcome if you have.
You wouldn't say that
if you knew what I am.
I'm past help. Nobody's past help.
If you mean you're a
prostitute, you should know
it is true of every woman who has
come here to rebuild their lives.
I'm helping them and I hope I
can help you, too. That's right.
Why not come in and help us
rebuild our lives? (LAUGHTER)
That's not why I'm here.
That is, I am a... what you said
but I don't want help, not for myself,
but...
When I make up my mind... I'm
sorry, this has been a mistake.
Please, please, don't
go, not again. (LAUGHTER)
It must be strange to receive
a letter from a dead man.
It's very strange.
We're leaving.
I'm sorry, Mr Charkham, to snatch him away.
That's quite all right, Lady
Mary. There will be papers to sign.
Yes, I expect there will.
Papa's asked Anthony to meet us there
so we can all face the future together.
He's bringing Isobel and Granny.
It's hard for your grandmother.
It's torture for all of us,
and if I ever look like I'm
finding it easy to lose my home
then I am putting on act.
Are you sure you can
manage this? Quite sure.
It's nothing hot. It's
not a shooting lunch.
Give them Champagne. That'll allow
you time to set it out properly.
I'll manage. What's this
place we're visiting?
One of His Lordship's houses. I
wonder why they're going there today.
Maybe he likes to keep
a check on things. Maybe.
See you there. Off you go.
She was a cousin of Granny's.
Do you want to come with us? Yes.
Thank you. Might I have a word, My Lady?
Of course. What is it? This
is a slightly awkward request,
what with the wedding tomorrow... Tell me.
Mrs Hughes is very tired.
I wonder if it might be possible
to divert some of her work my way?
I don't understand. What do you mean tired?
Cora...
Carson?
The fact is Mrs Hughes is ill,
My Lady. She may be very ill.
I'm extremely sorry to
trouble you with this
at such a moment, but I don't
want the wedding to sink her.
Of course not, but how will we manage
without O'Brien and now Mrs Hughes?
Miss O'Brien? She told
Molesley... Cora, please.
I'm coming.
Mrs Bartlett?
I've brought the money.
It's your loss cos I've got nothing to say.
All I want to know is if Vera ever...
Oh. So you were on Christian
name terms, were you?
You do surprise me.
If Mrs Bates ever suggested
she was depressed or unhappy...
Of course she was unhappy.
Her husband had left her
and gone off with a trollop.
He'd changed, you know. She
was scared of him by the end.
And now we know she had good reason.
When did you last see her?
You'd better come inside.
Bates.
Watch out.
What do you mean? Search
your room, search your bed.
They've set you up, your
cellmate and his mates.
Stop talking!
Just do it.
Her door was open so I looked in.
She was cooking, but
she had to post a letter
so we walked me down the street.
She said Bates was coming
back later for his tea.
She was terrified.
She was in a strange mood,
jumpy, fearful,
but determined.
She'd made pastry, she
scrubbed it out of her nails
like she didn't care if
she took the skin off.
So after she posted the letter
she went home on her own?
She did, poor soul, and
I never saw her after.
I can remember her now
walking away down the street.
It was raining. No, not
raining, more like drizzle.
The gaslight seemed to make
a sort of halo around her.
A halo? Really?
You can laugh.
When did you hear she was dead?
Next day.
Somehow, I knew it was Bates.
When I heard the verdict,
I thought he'd swing.
He should've if the
country hadn't gone soft.
(CRIES)
This is very good of you.
Nonsense, we were on the way.
I wish you'd let me sit in the
front. I prefer it, I've ridden
in the front seat many times.
Aren't you a wild thing!
There's never been a safer method
of travel. Nor a faster one.
Edith's the speed fiend, she
likes to go at a terrific lick.
Do you think you'll be able
to keep up with her? I'll try.
What's this place like? Do you know it?
A little. My late husband
kept the shooting there.
We'd sometimes have luncheon
in the house. Is it nice?
Nice enough, as a retreat from the world.
I wouldn't have thought
it suited to much else.
Downton Place.
How lovely.
Won't it be a bit cramped?  For most
people it looks like a fairy palace.
We'll be able to run it
with a much smaller staff.
This is it. We won't need
more than eight servants, tops.
So it'll be very economical. It...
What about me? Where am I to go?
We still own most of the village.
Oh. Perhaps I could open a shop?
Good idea, Granny. What
do you think it needs?
If it's like everywhere else, good
manners and decent conversation.
Then you should have a
roaring trade in minutes.
How's everything going? Very well.
It's unfair Mary had an
archbishop to marry her
and you've got poor old Mr Travis.
I don't mind, it's such short
notice, he was booked up.
I prefer it, really, to have
the man who christened us. Hm.
What did Charkham come for?
He gave me a letter from Swire.
He left one for each of
the three potential heirs
when and if they inherited.
Mine is the only one
to have been delivered.
What did it say?
I haven't opened it.
I can't decide whether I will.
Why wouldn't you? Because I
know it'll be a paean of praise,
how Lavinia could not have
found a better man, etc.
And you don't want to read that?
She could not have found a worse one.
No, I don't. I feel bad
enough and if I read his words
they will stay with me forever.
Ah.
Mrs Crawley? We're back
from our delicious luncheon
and I was on my way home.
You had a maid at Downton, Ethel Parks.
I was here when she brought
her son into the dining room.
Who could forget that? Do
you have an address for her?
I do, if she's still there.
You see...
You see, I saw her this morning
and I'm afraid she's fallen into a bad way.
A very bad way. Oh, dear.
I am sorry to hear that.
If you'd like to come with me,
I'll fetch it for you. Thank you.
(KEYS JANGLE)
(KEY TURNS IN LOCK)
Get up, both of you! Against the wall!
Mr Turner, search the bunk, please.
Nothing here. What?
Clean this mess up!
(DOOR IS LOCKED)
Bastards!
There's a lot of bastards in here.
Oh, right. I expect you're tired.
It's a long day up to London  and back.
Worth the journey? Not really.
Miss O'Brien, might I ask what
you've confided in Mr Molesley
but have kept from the rest of
us? I don't know what you mean.
Mr Molesley has given Her Ladyship
the impression you're planning
a change of some sort. What's this?
I'm sorry, I thought
Her Ladyship would know.
Know what?
That you're leaving.
I beg your pardon?
How dare you make such an assumption!
Isn't it time for the
dressing gong, Mr Carson?
It certainly is.  But... Excuse me,
Mr Molesley, I've got work to do,
even if you haven't.
I'll deal with you later.
You're in the soup. I wouldn't be
in her bad books for a gold clock.
You must've said something
Molesley misinterpreted.
I say nothing to him beyond "Pass
the salt" and "Out of the way".
There must have been something.
I do feel let down, and
right on top of the wedding...
(KNOCK ON DOOR) You sent
for me, My Lady. Yes.
Thank you, O'Brien.
Mrs Hughes, I understand
that you're not well.
Whom do you understand that
from? Because if the doctor...
It wasn't Doctor Clarkson.
It is not confirmed that
I am ill, Your Ladyship.
I've had a test and I'm
waiting for the results,
but I am perfectly capable...
Mrs Hughes, I only want to say one thing,
that if you are ill you are welcome
here for as long as you want.
Lady Sybil will help us to
find a suitable nurse. I see.
I don't want you to have
concerns about where you'll go
or who'll look after you. The
answer is here and we will.
I don't know what to say, My Lady.
There's isn't anything more to
say until we know where we stand.
Thank you.
He thinks I don't know
but, of course, I do.
We'll spend two weeks in Rome,
then Florence, then Venice,
so I couldn't be happier.
What about Loxley? Is there masses
to be done? It's not too bad.
It's not too bad downstairs.
The bedrooms are killers.
Don't do anything too fast, it takes
time to know how a house works.
You really should go to bed.
No bride wants to look tired.
It either means she's
anxious or been up to no good.
I won't sleep a wink. Tonight or tomorrow?
Sybil, vulgarity is no substitute for wit.
You started it.
(GIGGLING)
Miss O'Brien?
Please understand I didn't mean any harm.
Why make it up in the first place?
I didn't make it up, I
was told. Who told you?
Mr Barrow mentioned it, but I
think  it was an honest mistake.
No, it wasn't honest
and it wasn't a mistake,
but don't worry about it, I
can tell it wasn't your fault,
so we'll forget about it, shall we?
And when you see Mr Barrow,
you can tell him I may make
some honest mistakes myself.
No doubt we'll find out.
Probably the hard way.
Why not eat with us?
Oh, I couldn't do that.
Daisy won't sit down, the
invitation is not in your gift.
She eats with Mrs Patmore in the kitchen.
Fancy a game of something later?
Daisy's busy.
Anna? I want to write a letter. Sorry.
I'll play. Let's see how we feel.
What do you mean you've read it?
It wasn't right to destroy a man's
last words without reading them.
It wasn't your decision.
I made it my decision.
Do you want to hear what he says? No.
Lavinia must have written
to him on her last day
hours before she died. Nonsense.
No letter was in her room.
She wrote to him after she tried to
persuade you to call off the wedding.
This is quite impossible.
"She loved and admired you for
the sacrifice of your happiness.
She commended you to my care."
I can't listen to any
more of this. You must.
"I have few intimates so have
added you to my list of heirs.
It's unlikely I'll outlive the first two
so there's little chance
of you reading this.
If you do and the money has come to you,
know it is with my full
knowledge of what transpired.
Do not allow grief, guilt or regret
to hold you back in its employment.
God bless you, my boy. Reggie."
Are you sure you didn't write it?
I'm not accusing you of faking it,
but I suspect someone has.
So it won't change your mind?
Not yet it won't.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Time you were in bed.
It's a big day tomorrow.
I'll just finish this.
Is there something I can do for you?
No.
Did you say anything
about me to Her Ladyship?
I don't know what you mean. Why?
Don't worry. She was very kind and...
I was touched.
As you know, I don't worship them all,
like you do. I wouldn't put it like that.
But this time, I freely admit it
I was quite touched.
Am I interrupting? No, please, I
just want to ask you all something.
I'm sorry I've not been up. Don't
worry, I'll change after luncheon.
I had to catch you when
you were all together.
How can we help, My
Lady? It's a funny thing.
Mr Crawley has heard
Miss Swire sent a letter
on the day she died. If so,
someone must have posted it for her
and we wondered if it were any of you.
I'm afraid not. Given that the
poor lady passed away that same day,
an incident of this sort
would have been reported to me,
or to Mrs Hughes. That's right.
I see. Well, thank you very much.
What were that about? She wanted to
know if anyone had posted a letter
for Miss Swire.  Oh, I did that. Daisy?
What did you say?  She asked me
to put it in the box in the hall.
Why? What were you doing in her room?
Making up the fire. We started
talking, she'd written a letter.
She was ever so nice. I still
get  sad when I think about her.
And it didn't occur to you
to tell me?  Tell you what?
Never mind. I am grateful to you, Daisy.
You cannot know how much.
Well, this is the last of them.
I'm glad they've hurried it
so she can be married from Downton.
Are you? A little sober reflection
would not have gone amiss.
Mama, let's try to be positive.
Of all of them, Anthony is the
most traditional choice. Robert,
Edith is beginning her
life as an old man's drudge.
I shouldn't think a large
drawing room much compensation.
Why dwell on that now? To have the
pleasure of saying, "Told you so."
Now, the moment you
feel tired, you tell me,
I'll take over whatever it is
you're doing. Oh, will you now?
Are you sure you want
to come to the church?
You could stay here and have a lie down.
It would be so nice
if people would wait to learn if I
really am ill before boxing me up.
I don't know what you mean?
I don't know anything about any illness.
(SIGHS) Don't you?
I see.
Who told him? I don't know.
Maybe he just picked it up
somehow. He's worried about you.
He's a good man. He's a hopeless liar.
That's quite nice, really, isn't it?
I've had a message from the doctor.
He'll have the results tomorrow.
I'm to call in the afternoon.
Try not to worry.
(SIGHS) I'll try, but I won't succeed.
(SIGHS)
(DOOR OPENS)
That's it, I'll put the hat on later.
Go straight to Lady Edith.
You look marvellous. I feel marvellous.
That is, I feel marvellous because
we don't have to leave Downton.
Lavinia did write to her father
and it was posted from this house.
In other words, every word Mr
Swire wrote in that letter was true.
(SIGHS) Daisy posted it.
The kitchen maid.
I see. Do you, my darling?
I hope so, because if you
try to find one more excuse
not to accept the money, I'll
have to beat you about the head.
I see.
(SIGHS)
I do have one condition, however.
Make it a good one. Let's
not steal Edith's thunder.
I'll tell Robert after it's
over and she's left on honeymoon.
Now, that I can live with.
You look beautiful.
All of us married. All of us happy.
And the first baby on the way.
Let's get a picture of the three
of us when we get to the church.
He looks as if he's waiting for
a beating from the headmaster.
Do you think I should reassure him?
How? He's done it before so he must
be in possession of all the facts.
Perhaps the first Lady Strallan
was a difficult act to follow.
Or a difficult one to repeat.
Well, fashionably late is one thing.
Are we going in? Edith, I know
we haven't always got along,
and I doubt things'll
change much in the future,
but today I wish you all
the luck in the world.
Thank you.
Oh, look.
Thank you very much.
(ORGAN STARTS PLAYING)
Good afternoon.
Good afternoon, my sweet one.
Dearly beloved, we are gathered...
I can't do this. (ALL GASP) What?
I can't do it.
You know it's wrong, you
said so. My dear chap...
No, I shouldn't have  let it get this far.
I should've stopped it long
ago.  I tried to stop it.
What are you saying?
I don't understand what you're saying.
Edith...
Edith, I can't let you throw
away  your life like this.
What do you mean?
We're so happy, aren't we?
We're going to be so
terribly, terribly happy.
You are going to be happy,
I pray that you are,
but only if you don't
waste yourself on me.
Anthony, it is too late for this.
Might I suggest we take a step back?
No, let him go. Let him
go. You know he's right.
Don't stop him doing the
only sensible thing in months.
Thank you, Lady Grantham. But Granny!
It's over, dear, don't drag it out.
Wish him well and let him go.
I can't.  Goodbye,  my dearest darling,
and may God bless you...
always.
But...
Oh, quick.
(WEEPS)
When everyone gets back,
can you clear all this away?
I want it gone before Lady Edith
comes downstairs. Everything.
Ask the outside staff to help put
back the carpet and the furniture.
(DOOR OPENS)
Is there anything I could
say to make it better? No.
Look at them, with their husbands...
Sybil pregnant, Mary probably pregnant.
Just go!
I mean it, go! Perhaps you should go.
Oh, Mama.
You are being tested,
and do you know what they say, my darling?
Being tested only makes you stronger.
I don't think it's working with me.
What shall we do now?
There's nothing we can do
beyond removing all signs of a wedding
and holding her hand while she recovers.
She will, of course.
Meanwhile, it's time to face
the business of leaving Downton.
Without the wedding to hide behind,
there's no reason to delay it
and astonish the world with the
extent of my wretched failure.
Actually,
Mary and I intended to make
an announcement at dinner.
What announcement? What
about? You don't have to leave.
I'll explain it later, but...
I'm going to give you Reggie's money.
I'll accept it. I'll give it to you.
Don't be silly, you're not
going to give me any money.
I am. You don't want to leave.
Nor does Mary.
Nor do any of us for that matter.
I still won't take your money.
What I will allow is for
you to invest in the place.
If we stay, you'll share the
ownership, it'll be your house,
your estate as much as mine.
We will be joint masters.
And if you won't agree, I will
sell and it will all be your fault.
I never thought I'd feel
sorry for an earl's daughter.
All God's creatures have their troubles.
Anna... Yes?
Do you think it's right women
should say what they think?
Speak out about romance and everything?
Well, things are changing for
us and the vote won't be long now
so they must get used
to us speaking our minds.
But what? With most of
the men I've ever met,
if you started to court them,
they'd be so terrified they'd run a mile.
Has she had something to eat?
Anna took up some sandwiches.
She didn't touch a thing.
That reminds me. Carson, I don't
want Edith to see any wedding food.
Mrs Hughes and Anna are taking
what's left to Mr Travis tomorrow
for the poor. If the poor don't
want it, bring it over to me.
How can we help Edith? By
finding her something to do.
Is this all we're
getting? The pickety bits?
Hardly. These are canapes, Alfred.
For your first course,
truffle egg on toast, perhaps?
Oysters a la russe.
Then what? There's lobster
rissoles in mousseline sauce.
Or calvados-glazed duckling. Or
maybe a little asparagus salad
with Champagne saffron vinaigrette.
When I think how you've
gone to such pains...
What about the pain of
that poor girl upstairs?
Jilted at the alter... I
couldn't stand the shame.
Then it's lucky no-one's ever asked you.
Poor thing. How will she find
the strength to hold up her head?
I'd have to run away and hide
in a place where no-one knew me.
She's well out of it. How can you say it?
She's young, she's not bad looking,
she could do much better than
that broken-down old crock.
Sir Anthony may have betrayed
a daughter of this house
but he doesn't deserve to be
addressed like that by a footman.
Oh, I think he does. Every
bit of that and worse.
Well, maybe just this once.
Right, what's it to be?
Lobster, duck or asparagus?
Is there any cheese?
What would you like me to get you?
A different life.
Let me bring you up some breakfast.
No.
I'm a useless spinster,
good at helping out, that is my role,
and spinsters get up for breakfast.
(KNOCK ON DOOR)
Going out? Just into the village.
I... have to fetch something.
Can I help?
I'm going down later.
No, thank you.
This is an errand I have to do for myself.
Ready?
As ready as I'll ever be.
(DOOR CLOSES)
You know that's not true.
You can be sure of one thing.
I won't be cured by standing here.
Do you want... No.
Everything all right, Miss O'Brien?
Oh, yes, everything's all right with me,
but it'll be all wrong with you
before too long, mark my words.
Oh? And how is that, Miss O'Brien?
I don't know, not yet,
but it will be.
You can be sure of it.
Well?
Is it or isn't it? It's not cancer.
It's a benign something or other.
Nothing more.
Don't mention that you've said anything.
She doesn't know that I know.
I won't say a word.
Did you tell him? I would prefer
to say I put him out of his misery.
(MR CARSON SINGS)
♪ Dashing away with the smoothing iron
♪ She stole my heart away
♪ She stole my heart away ♪
Hm.
I haven't had a letter
from Mr Bates in weeks.
He wants me to make a new life without him.
Am I to answer to you both? I have
made an investment. That's all.
You abandon a pregnant woman in
a foreign land and run for it?!
Other men have normal families.
No family is ever what it seems.
Tell them I'm all right. Sybil? Hello?
itfc subtitles